## **Daehwa Kim**

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs and (b) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated <b>hand inputs</b>	sensing and interaction techniques for a <b>mobile device</b>
for Fluid Interfaces	AtaTouch (Cond. Accepted CHl'21) +     MagTouch (CHl'20)	<ul><li>OddEyeCam (UIST'20)</li><li>OmniSense (Ongoing)</li></ul>

#### **EDUCATION**

#### KAIST, Human-Computer Interaction Lab

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- M.S. in School of Computing
  - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
  - Focus: Sensing Techniques
  - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)
    - o Thesis Committee: Geehyuk Lee (Chair), Juho Kim, Uichin Lee

#### **UNIST**, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
  - B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
  - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
  - Entered with top honors.
  - Graduated with Magna Cum Laude
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

#### Jul 2018

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### CONFERENCES

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" To Appear in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, To Appear) Honorable Mention Award
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### HCI Lab, KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- $\bullet\,$  Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
- Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
- · Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

#### Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

• Research Intern, IoT Research Division

Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

- Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
- · Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim
- Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing

#### iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST

- Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering
- Feb 2017 Nov 2017

- · Project: Finger Joystick Interaction
- Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko

• Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization

## AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

#### Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

Mar 2021

<u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" To Appear in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

#### Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

 Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

#### 4th Prize, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award

Dec 2017

- Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction".
- Awarded by NAVER CEO.
- Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW.

#### Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016

Dec 2016

- Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university students.
- Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency.
- Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1.

#### Dean's List, UNIST

■ 2017 Fall Dean's List: GPA 4.05/4.3	Jan 2018
<ul> <li>2017 Spring Dean's List: GPA 3.98/4.3</li> </ul>	Jul 2017
<ul> <li>2016 Fall Dean's List: GPA 3.90/4.3</li> </ul>	Feb 2016
<ul> <li>2016 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.06/4.3</li> </ul>	Aug 2016
■ 2015 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.00/4.3	Jul 2015
Uni-Star Scholarshin UNIST	Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

#### **Uni-Star Scholarship**, UNIST

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

• Entered with top honors.

■ Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester.

#### Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST

Jun 2018

• Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNISTSep 2018 − Dec 2018Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNISTFeb 2017 − Dec 2017Instructor, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT)Jul 2016 − Sep 2016Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

#### Reviewer

■ CHI '21 LBW

#### CAMPUS ACTIVITIES

#### D2 factory, NAVER

Campus Partner
 Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE

#### HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST

• A computer security & development research group

Vice-President
 Head of Android development team
 Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members

Feb 2016 – Feb 2017
Feb 2017 – Dec 2017

#### **UNIST Media Center**, UNIST

■ Video Editor Mar 2015 – Feb 2017

Representative work

- My Age 22 Travel to Europe with a drone
- Web drama: The town where engineers live

#### PROJECTS

#### Audio Hero

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

- Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model
- Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing

**VRone** Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

■ 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone

• Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming System Light 2.0 @ ETRI Jan 2018 - Mar 2018 • Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing **VibCat** Oct 2017 – Dec 2017 • Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction Skills: Machine learning, Android programming Finger joystick interaction Feb 2017 - Nov 2017 • Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen • Skills: Machine learning, Android programming Poem a moment Mar 2017 - Jun 2017 • An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper Available on Google Play store (download 1000+) Skills: Android programming **TUIT Android Lecture** Jun 2016 - Sep 2016 • Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students • Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming Jun 2016 - Jul 2016

Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way

Available on Google Play store (download 500+)

Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2021-03-15 for Acme Corporation]